Guide to the Ann Weisgarber Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
- Accession 2017-096, This accession consists of archival materials relating to the writing career of author, Ann Weisgarber from 1989-2017. Majority of the materials in the collection are research and drafts for Weisgarber's various works such as The Personal History of Rachel DuPree and The Promis
  - "The Promise-Skyhorse"; The Promise Press Release, Author Questionnaire, and The Promise corrections and additions for Skyhorse Publishing, July 25, 2013 (Box 2641, Folder 12)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Viking Copy Edits ARC"; Notes from Penguin Publishing, Badlands National Park postcard, and press release for Rachel DuPree, August 30, 2010 - November 8, 2010 (Box 2641, Folder 13)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Viking Copy Edits ARC-Professional The Promise"; Correspondence on The Promise, March 4, 2013 - May 15, 2013 (Box 2641, Folder 14)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Viking Copy Edits ARC"; Annotated The Personal History of Rachel DuPree Viking copy editor galley proofs, undated (Box 2641, Folder 15)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Viking Copy Edits ARC"; The Personal History of Rachel DuPree galley proofs Viking-U.S. editor, undated (Box 2641, Folder 16)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Page from Imprint Success stories review of Rachel DuPree, and Imprint Annual Report, 2007-2008 (Box 2641, Folder 17)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Articles and reviews about Rachel DuPree, August - November 2010 (Box 2641, Folder 18)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Magazines with articles on Rachel DuPree-Ebony, WORLD, Texas Monthly, and Red, July 2008 - August 2012 (Box 2641, Folder 19)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Book Passage review, Meet the Author, and Austin American-Statesman reviews, September - October 2010 (Box 2641, Folder 20)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Debut authors for Barnes & Noble, New York Times reviews, articles for Weisgarber's website, and Ohioana Award Finalist, 2010-2011 (Box 2641, Folder 21)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews-Events R.D."; South Dakota Festival of Books materials and awards, 2011-2015 (Box 2641, Folder 22)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; "Black Cowboys Rode the Trails, Too", website article, Western Writers of America, and correspondence, June 2009 - February 2013 (Box 2641, Folder 23)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Proclamation, correspondence, and reviews, 2013 (Box 2642, Folder 1)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Correspondence from readers & well-wishers-The Personal History of Rachel DuPree (1 of 2), June 10, 2008 - May 21, 2013 (Box 2642, Folder 2)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Correspondence from readers & well-wishers-The Personal History of Rachel DuPree (2 of 2), June 10, 2008 - May 21, 2013 (Box 2642, Folder 3)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Correspondence, March 25, 2009 - September 19, 2013 (Box 2642, Folder 4)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; Correspondence, August 21, 2006 - June 29, 2016 (Box 2642, Folder 5)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews-Rachel DuPree"; Book reviews in USA Today, Texas Monthly, and New York Times, 2008-2010 (Box 2642, Folder 6)
  - "Rachel DuPree-Readers Correspondence-Wash Co. Big Read-Reviews"; The Personal History of Rachel DuPree correspondence from readers and publicists, January 2, 2004 - August 26, 2011 (Box 2642, Folder 7)
  - "Gulf Coast Reads Posters for Readings"; The Promise-A novel by Ann Weisgarber, video made by Al Kazmer, CD, April 2012 (Box 2642, Folder 8)
  - "Gulf Coast Reads Posters for Readings"; Workshop writings, research for The Promise, articles for Weisgarber's website, and comments from writing group, August 2006 - January 2013 (Box 2642, Folder 9)
  - "Floppy diskettes-early drafts of The Promise"; Note with floppies says there are printed copies, July 2009 - January 2010 (Box 2642, Folder 10)
  - "Floppy diskettes-early drafts of The Personal History of Rachel DuPree"; Note with floppies states there are physical copies as well, September 30, 2002 - January 1, 2006 (Box 2642, Folder 11)
  - "Floppy diskettes for "Thanksgiving Found"-dropped manuscript"; Note states there are physical copies of this draft, November 2003 - 2008 (Box 2642, Folder 12)
  - "Floppy diskettes-early drafts of The Personal History of Rachel DuPree"; Note states there are printed copies of this draft, January 28, 2003 - January 01, 2006 (Box 2642, Folder 13)
  - Inserts from books placed in Backlog, most pertaining to the authors of the books and their connections to Weisgarber, December 10, 2010 (Box 2642, Folder 14)
  - South Coast Cooking: Cajun-Creole Meets Tex-Mex cookbook by Arch Andrus, 2007 (Box 2642, Folder 15)
  - A Feast from the Texas Hills cookbook from Bandera United Methodist Church, June 5, 2014 (Box 2642, Folder 16)
  - "Library Songs #5 Sweet [Evalina]" CD, "Best Seller!" book crown, and faux wood centerpiece with gold "W" for Georgetown, Texas, Library Author Lecture Series, 2014-2016 (Box 2642, Folder 17)
  - Pearl Beer San Antonio Brewing Association plate, a gift from a book club in San Antonio, undated (Box 2642, Folder 18)
  - Pen in a Cross case, a gift from Weisgarber's Writing Critique group, undated (Box 2642a, Folder 1)
  - Gulf Coast Reads: On the Same Page, travel coffee mug, given to Weisgarber for The Promise, undated (Box 2642a, Folder 2)
  - White and black teapot with musical notes, a gift from a book club because the teapot has musical notes on it that are in The Promise, 2015 (Box 2642a, Folder 3)
  - "Phenomenal Woman/ Journeys" white mug, a gift from Journey's Book Club in Houston, Texas, 2016 (Box 2642a, Folder 4)
  - "Go Away I'm Writing" white mug with green script, a gift from a book club for The Promise, undated (Box 2642a, Folder 5)
  - Clear cube with bronze coin from Pasadena Public Library that states "Your Exceptional Library Experience", a gift from the Gulf Coast Reads for The Promise, 2016 (Box 2642a, Folder 6)
  - Framed Items, undated
    Scope and Contents
    1. Framed cover art of The Personal History of Rachel DuPree, undated 2. Framed cover art of The Promise, undated
  - Oversized Items, 2015, undated (Map-case Dr. 3)
    1. Gulf Coast Reads On the Same Page, The Promise, poster, October 2015 2. LSC-North Harris Library Presents The Promise and the Writing Process with Author Ann Weisgarber, poster, October 15, undated 3. Hill Country Author Series Presents Ann Weisgarber, author of The Promise at Georgetown Public Library, poster, November 17, undated 4. Two Gulf Coast Reads, The Forum at Cypress Creek Christian Church, author talk and book signing posters, October 29, [2015] 5. Gulf Coast Reads Meet Author Ann Weisgarber at Mitchell Library, Spur Award Finalist BestHistorical Fiction, Walter Scott Prize Shortlist, October 8, 2015
- Accession 2019-050, Archival materials received from Ann Weisgarber. Majority of the materials pertaining to research and drafts of her novel, The Glovemaker. Correspondence e-mails with her editor, Josie Humber, and publishing company Mantle/ MacMillian of the UK, as well as, a film offer for The Personal History of Rachel Dupree. Included are many revisions of chapters 1-23 of The Glovemaker (Excluding chapter 16). Ann Weisgarber was on the TIF council for "Texas Institute of Letters- 82nd annual Awards Banquet" which awarded recipients Sandra Cisneros, Bill Wittliff, and Jan Reid amongst many others.
  - Manila folder titled "For Fun" includes a thank you letter from the Wittliff Collections dated June 11, 2018 and letter written to Laura Bush December 26,2000; Manilla folder marked "The Glovemaker- Nagel & Kimche-Zurich (German Translation) including email exchanges between Anne Weisgarber and her agent, Anna Halton and the German offer for The Glovemaker by publishing company Nagel & Kimche, corrections and comments byKatherine Razum (German Translator), & Exchanges with German editor-Patricia Reimann. November 16, 2017- November 9, 2018; Manila folder"From Readers" including two cards from fans, abstract water colored card with pressed flower; Manila folder "Film option-The Personal History of Rachel Dupree" including correspondence between Ann Weisgarber, Producer Brian Armstrong/Brian Rosen, Harriet Sonders- Former rights Director of MacMillan UK, director/Screenwriter Claire McCarthy, Agent Margaret Halton, August 2017-October 2018. Contract for JuVee Productions renewal August 29, 2018. (Box 2965, Folder 1)
  - Manila folder titled "Events" includes printed brochure "The Bosque Arts Center Presents: Books on the Bosque" invitation to hear review of The Personal History of Rachel Dupree, "The Art of Business: Taking a Novel Approach to Business" booklet with article on Ann Weisgarber, Invitation to a reading with Ann Weisgarber in Galveston, "Texas Institute of Letters- 82nd annual Awards Banquet" program includes Sandra Cisneros, Bill Wittliff, Jan Reid and memorials for Elroy Bode, Bill Crider, Audrey Slate, April 7, 2018; Manila folder "Rejections of The Glovemaker by John Sicilano- Penguin Random House" includes correspondence with Jon Mitchell, MacMillan, Rejection from Viking, Considerations for Skyhorse July 19, 2017; Manila folder "The Glovemaker-UK Mantle" correspondence with Editor Josie Humber and Marie Ryt, includes written annotations on letter exchanges between characters "Deborah" and "Samuel" & book's launch on Amazon, November 2017- August 2018. (Box 2965, Folder 2)
  - Manila folder titled "Correspondence with Margaret Halton-Agent in the UK" includes The Glovemaker's title options: Manila folder "Research- The Dressmaker" includes calendar from 1888-1887 with nots on novels dates and events, printouts of information on Utah and Mormonism, printout on indigenous trees of Utah, printout on the 49th Congressional Act, April, 2016-November 22, 2017; Manila folder "Research-The Glovemaker- Utah Research" includes handwritten notes, printout on Utah State University's "The United States Marshals in Utah Territory to 1896" thesis and dissertation by Vernal A. Brown (1970) with annotations by Ann Weisgarber. 1970-November 22, 2017. (Box 2965, Folder 3)
  - Manila folder "The Glovemaker- UK Mantle/Pan MacMillian- copy/edits with Mary Chamberlain 'Proofreader'" includes several correspondences regarding edits November 16, 2017- April 2018; Manila folder "Prologue revisions- The Glovemaker" with heavy annotations; Manila folder "The Glovemaker-Chapter One" printouts of Chapter One and several revisions. May 27, 2012- May 24, 2017 (Box 2965, Folder 4)
  - Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Two" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Three" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Four" printouts of revisions. March 2015- May 24, 2017. (Box 2965, Folder 5)
  - Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Six" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "First Letter" printout of "Samuel Tyler's letters; "Manila folder "Third Letter" printout of "Samuel Tyler's" third letter; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Seven" printouts of revisions. December 2012-August 10, 2017. (Box 2965, Folder 6)
  - Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Eight" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Nine" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Ten" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Eleven" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Twelve" printouts of revisions. August 2013- May 27, 2017. (Box 2965, Folder 7)
  - Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Thirteen" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Fourteen" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter fifteen" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter seventeen" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Eighteen" printouts of revisions; July 2016- May 27, 2017. (Box 2965, Folder 8)
  - Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Nineteen" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Twenty" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Twenty-One" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Twenty-Two" printouts of revisions; Manila folder "The Glovemaker- Chapter Twenty-Three" printouts of revisions. November 6, 2016- August 1, 2017. (Box 2965, Folder 9)
  - Printed copy of original version of "The Convergence" later re-named, The Glovemaker, sent to agent Margaret Halton., December 22, 2016 (Box 2965, Folder 10)
  - Printed copy of The Glovemaker with first editorial notes by Josie Humber-Mantle/MacMillian in the UK, May 3, 2017 (Box 2965, Folder 11)
  - Printed copy and correspondence with Josie Humber (Editor for Mantle/MacMillian in the UK) on The Glovemaker's second edits, May 23, 2017 - June 2017 (Box 2965, Folder 12)
  - Printed copy of The Glovemaker with digital edits by Josie Humber editor of Mantle and MacMillian (UK) and annotations by Ann Weisgarber, August 3, 2017 (Box 2965, Folder 13)
  - First working draft of The Glovemaker edits requested by Josie Humber editor of Mantle/MacMillian of the UK with annotation by Ann Weisgarber, August 3, 2017 (Box 2965, Folder 14)
  - Printed copy of The Glovemaker before third round of edits from Josie Humber editor of Mantle/MacMillian of the UK, August 10, 2017 (Box 2965, Folder 15)
  - Printed copy of The Glovemaker with corrections for edited copy; Printed copy of Josie Humber's digital edits as editor for Mantle/ MacMillian of the UK and Ann Weisgarber's annotations; The Glovemaker line edits and revisions, August 10, 2017 - September 1, 2017 (Box 2965, Folder 16)
  - Printed copy of second writing draft with revisions of The Glovemaker and added annotations by Ann Weisgarber, August 3, 2017 - September 1, 2017 (Box 2965, Folder 17)
  - Printed copy of The Glovemaker with revisions and annotations sent to Josie Humber, Editor for Mantle/MacMillian of the UK, September 25, 2017 (Box 2966, Folder 1)
  - Printed copy of The Glovemaker with copy edits by Mary Chamberlain, Copy Editor for Mantle/MacMillian of the UK, September 25, 2017 (Box 2966, Folder 2)
  - Printed copy of The Glovemaker with digital responses to copy edits, November-December 2017 (Box 2966, Folder 3)
  - Printed page proofs of The Glovemaker by Mantle/ MacMillian and annotations by Ann Weisgarber, March 17-18, 2017 (Box 2966, Folder 4)
  - Print outs of correspondence with Kate Tolley of Mantle/ MacMillian of the UK over page proofs of The Glovemaker; Printed page proofs with corrections, April 13, 2018 (Box 2966, Folder 5)
  - The Glovemaker printed proofs from Mantle/ MacMillian and read by Rob Weisgarber, March 3, 2018 (Box 2966, Folder 6)
  - Printed acknowledgment page for The Promise; US edition page proofs from Skyhorse for The Glovemaker, May 10, 2018 (Box 2966, Folder 7)